<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A sea kayak story</title>
    <link>https://microp11.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A sea kayak story</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://microp11.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trip</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/trip/leg1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/trip/leg1/</guid>
      <description>2023: North Rustico to Cap Egmont, 9 days, 200 nautical miles or 370 km.&#xA;2024: Cap Egmont to North Rustico, hopefully 5-6 days at most, weather permitting, roughly 100 nautical miles left.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Provisions</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-provisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-provisions/</guid>
      <description>Provisions&#xA;Same as with the equipment, the aim is to be self-sufficient for the entire trip, and only the water should need replenishing.&#xA;Based on the dry-run, for a 10+h day paddle I would need about 3k calories. Adding to that the 2.5k for the average male body, it seems that 5.5k calories a day would be a good guess.&#xA;I should be drinking water and eating frequently enough to avoid getting light-headed while on the water.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEI-go-round with Xeon Kayak Ergometer</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/dry-run/log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/dry-run/log/</guid>
      <description>This is not the actual trip. This is just training mapped on chart to have an idea of what the real thing might be.&#xA;May 14, 2023, lap2&#xA;28 days on ergo, 263 nautical miles, 490 km&#xA;Stats&#xA;March 10, 2023, lap1&#xA;33 days on ergo, 281 nautical miles, 522 km&#xA;Stats&#xA;Xeon is a heavy-use Kayak Ergometer, that gives a true feel of on-the-water paddling.&#xA;Xeon ergometer shaft to paddle length</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Equipment</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-equipment/</guid>
      <description>Equipment.&#xA;The aim is to be self-sufficient for the entire trip. Wherever possible, the equipment will be packed in 5L dry bags.&#xA;Based on C2TC Sea Kayak Coaching expedition gear check list. Camping gear Small compact tent (stored in a plastic bag) Sleeping bag (stored in a plastic bag inside a compression bag) Inflatable sleeping mattress (the thicker the better) and inflatable pillow Headlamp and tent lamp Paddling gear Sea kayak with deck compass Paddle and spare paddle 2 inflatable paddle floats Sponge and bilge pump Chart case and charts GPS and batteries (4 AA per 3 days, duracell type) Kits First aid kit Boat repair kit Toilet kit (1 roll toilet paper, alcohol wipes, 1 lighter, headlamp) Ouch kit (band-aids, pain killers, antacid, antibiotic ointment) Cooking kit (stove, 1 fuel canister, 1 lighter, cooking pot, knife) Clothing on the water (synthetic or wool) One thermal layer (tops and bottoms) Long sleeve sweater Socks Dry suit Spray skirt Personal PFD (whistle, watch, strobe, handheld compass, grease pen, 2L hydration pack, VHF, GPS) Footwear Ball cap Tow line Tow rope Neoprene mitts Sun glasses with straps Clothing when not on water (synthetic or wool) Ski hat or toque Rain gear (light), tops and bottoms Two more thermal layers (tops and bottoms, sockes) Insulation layer (fleece jacket) Light shoes with a hard sole (crocs) Other items Clock or extra watch with alarm Extra ball cap Glasses Small mirror Sun screen Bug repellant Small towel Pocket knife Notebook, pen, voice recorder Eating thermos Eating utensils (spoon, fork) 3 chemical light sticks One extra rope Two Ikea carrying bags Phone, battery pack, and cable Solar charger Extra plastic bags _</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Contingencies</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-contingencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-contingencies/</guid>
      <description>By far the biggest hazard on this trip is paddling alone and I strongly believe that I am prepared.&#xA;Emergency contacts printed on a card on boat:&#xA;VHF channel 16 In Atlantic Canada cell dialing *16 takes you directly to the Joint Rescue Coordination Centre (JRCC) Halifax 911 Coast Guard Toll-free: 1-800-565-1582 Telephone: 902-427-8200 Personal In terms of geography, there are areas on this trip where there are high cliffs and it is impossible to land.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The route</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-route/</guid>
      <description>With the goal clear in my mind, first step was to figure out &amp;ldquo;when&amp;rdquo;. I think that for PEI, the months of June and July are the best for a multi-day paddle. The waters start warming up, there are no bugs, it is not excessively warm which means that there is no significant weather either, and the daylight time is at its longest.&#xA;Direction of travel: The next step was to see which way to proceed: clockwise or counter-clockwise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Goal</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-goal/</guid>
      <description>For some time now I was pondering on the idea of circumnavigating Prince Edward Island in a sea kayak. There are roughly around 300 nautical miles (555 km) if one is to follow the shore closely, save some if paddling straight lines from one point of a large bay to another.&#xA;A few people have done this already, and it is only fair to assume that there are more:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
