<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A sea kayak story</title>
    <link>https://microp11.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A sea kayak story</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microp11.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Provisions [TODO]</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-provisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-provisions/</guid>
      <description>Provisions
Same as with the equipment, the aim is to be self-sufficient for the entire trip, and only the water should need replenishing.
Based on the dry-run, in perfect conditions, for a 9-10h paddle a day I would need about 3k calories. Add to that 2.5k for the average male body, it seems that 5.5k calories a day would be the minimum I would need during this trip.
TODO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PEI-go-round with Xeon Kayak Ergometer</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/dry-run/log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/dry-run/log/</guid>
      <description>February 8, 2023
104.3 nautical miles, or 194 Km Stats Xeon is a heavy-use Kayak Ergometer, that gives a true feel of on-the-water paddling.
Xeon ergometer shaft to paddle length The correct way to manage fear is to gradually broaden your comfort zone until your comfort zone includes things that seemed previously impossible. Alex Honnold _</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Equipment</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-equipment/</guid>
      <description>Equipment.
The aim is to be self-sufficient for the entire trip. Wherever possible, the equipment will be packed in 5L dry bags.
Based on C2TC Sea Kayak Coaching expedition gear check list. Camping gear Small compact tent Sleeping bag and liner (stored in a plastic bag inside a compression bag) Inflatable sleeping mattress (the thicker the better) Paddling gear Sea kayak with deck compass Paddle and spare paddle 2 inflatable paddle floats Pump and sponge Chart case and charts GPS and batteries Kits First aid kit Boat repair kit Toilet kit (toilet paper, alcohol wipes, lighter, headlamp) Ouch kit (band-aids, pain killers, antacid, alcohol wipes, lidocaine gel) Cooking kit (stove, fuel and lighters, small kettle, cooking pot, frying pan, knife and cutting board, ladle, tongs, salt, pepper, spices, washing station) Coffee kit (coffee, filters, filter holder) Clothing on the water (synthetic or wool) One thermal layer (tops and bottoms) Long sleeve sweater Socks Dry suit Spray skirt Personal PFD (whistle, watch, strobe, handheld compass, grease pen, 2L hydration pack, VHF) Footwear Helmet Ball cap Light neoprene gloves Tow line Neoprene mitts (unsure) Clothing when not on water (synthetic or wool) Ski hat or toque Rain gear, tops and bottoms One more thermal layer (tops and bottoms) One pair quick dry pants Insulation layer (fleece jacket) Underwear Socks Light waterproof shoes Flip-flops (unsure) Other items 1 extra handheld compass Sun screen and sun glasses 3 headlamps and batteries (one in the toilet kit, one in the sleeping bag and one in the day hatch) Bug repellant Small towel Pocket knife Notebook, pen and pencil Thermos (with spoon) Eating utensils (bowl, plate, mug, knife, spoon, fork) Cuban YoYo (unsure) Tarp, rope, extra clips 3 chemical light sticks Plastic lunch box One extra rope One Ikea carrying bag Alcohol wipes Phone Solar charger (unsure) Compact hand saw On water snacks Extra garbage and small clear bags Camera Batteries _</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Contingencies</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-contingencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-contingencies/</guid>
      <description>By far the biggest hazard on this trip is paddling alone and I strongly believe that I am prepared.
Emergency contacts printed on a card on boat:
VHF channel 16 911 Coast Guard Toll-free: 1-800-565-1582 Telephone: 902-427-8200 Personal In terms of geography, there are areas on this trip where there are high cliffs and it is impossible to land. Due to the positioning of the island in St. Lawrence Bay, there is very little swell on PEI and that greatly increases one&amp;rsquo;s peace of mind regarding unexpected water behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The route</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-route/</guid>
      <description>With the goal clear in my mind, first step was to figure out &amp;ldquo;when&amp;rdquo;. I think that for PEI, the months of June and July are the best for a multi-day paddle. The waters start warming up, there are no bugs, it is not excessively warm which means that there is no significant weather either, and the daylight time is at its longest.
The next step was to see which way to proceed: clockwise or counter-clockwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goal</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/the-goal/</guid>
      <description>For some time now I was pondering on the idea of circumnavigating Prince Edward Island in a sea kayak. There are roughly around 300 nautical miles (555 km) if one is to follow the shore closely, save some if paddling straight lines from one point of a large bay to another.
A few people have done this already, and it is only fair to assume that there are more:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
