<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>equipment on A sea kayak story</title>
    <link>https://microp11.github.io/tags/equipment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in equipment on A sea kayak story</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://microp11.github.io/tags/equipment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Equipment and provisions</title>
      <link>https://microp11.github.io/planning/equipment-and-provisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://microp11.github.io/planning/equipment-and-provisions/</guid>
      <description>Equipment.
The aim is to be self-sufficient for the entire trip. Wherever possible, the equipment will be packed in 5L dry bags.
Based on C2TC Sea Kayak Coaching expedition gear check list. Camping gear Small compact tent Sleeping bag and liner (stored in a plastic bag inside a compression bag) Inflatable sleeping mattress (the thicker the better) Paddling gear Sea kayak with deck compass Paddle and spare paddle 2 inflatable paddle floats Pump and sponge Chart case and charts GPS and batteries Kits First aid kit Boat repair kit Toilet kit (toilet paper, alcohol wipes, lighter, headlamp) Ouch kit (band-aids, pain killers, antacid, alcohol wipes, lidocaine gel) Cooking kit (stove, fuel and lighters, small kettle, cooking pot, frying pan, knife and cutting board, ladle, tongs, salt, pepper, spices, washing station) Coffee kit (coffee, filters, filter holder) Clothing on the water (synthetic or wool) One thermal layer (tops and bottoms) Long sleeve sweater Socks Dry suit Spray skirt Personal PFD (whistle, watch, strobe, handheld compass, grease pen, 2L hydration pack, VHF) Footwear Helmet Ball cap Light neoprene gloves Tow line Neoprene mitts (unsure) Clothing when not on water (synthetic or wool) Ski hat or toque Rain gear, tops and bottoms One more thermal layer (tops and bottoms) One pair quick dry pants Insulation layer (fleece jacket) Underwear Socks Light waterproof shoes Flip-flops (unsure) Other items 1 extra handheld compass Sun screen and sun glasses 3 headlamps and batteries (one in the toilet kit, one in the sleeping bag and one in the day hatch) Bug repellant Small towel Pocket knife Notebook, pen and pencil Thermos (with spoon) Eating utensils (bowl, plate, mug, knife, spoon, fork) Cuban YoYo Tarp, rope, extra clips 3 chemical light sticks Plastic lunch box One extra rope One Ikea carrying bag Alcohol wipes Phone Solar charger (unsure) Compact hand saw On water snacks Extra garbage and small clear bags Camera Batteries Provisions</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
